{
    "id": "10338e79f7f6429e9706e830f0a3c195",
    "title": "Simple Past And Present Perfect",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I ......................................... him since last week.",
            "description": "The present perfect is common with the time expressions since and for.",
            "answers": [
                "did not see",
                "have not seen"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It .......................................... for hours.",
            "description": "Use the present perfect if it is still raining. ",
            "answers": [
                "rained",
                "has rained",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The train ...................................... 5 minutes ago.",
            "description": "The simple past is used to talk about finished events.",
            "answers": [
                "has left",
                "left"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She .......................................... from Madras University.",
            "description": "The simple past is the most common tense for talking about past events.",
            "answers": [
                "graduated",
                "has graduated"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She ..................................... homeless since she lost her job.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about actions or situations that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "What ........................................ then?",
            "description": "We use the simple past with time expressions referring to the past. ",
            "answers": [
                "did you do",
                "have you done"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ...................................... the parcel in the morning.",
            "description": "We use the simple past with past time expressions.",
            "answers": [
                "sent",
                "have sent"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ........................................ the letters.",
            "description": "When there is no time reference, we are more likely to use a present perfect for recently finished actions and situations.",
            "answers": [
                "posted",
                "have posted"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They .......................................... the contract last week.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "signed",
                "have signed"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "It ........................................ yesterday.",
            "description": "We use the simple past with past time expressions. ",
            "answers": [
                "rained",
                "has rained"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The train ............................................ yet.",
            "description": "The present perfect is more common with the expressions yet, already etc.",
            "answers": [
                "did not arrive",
                "has not arrived"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ......................................... to Australia.",
            "description": "The present perfect is more common with the expressions never and ever. ",
            "answers": [
                "never went",
                "have never been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}